Guide to the Marvin H. Pope Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Personal/Memorabilia, 1916-1998; Series VII
  - Newspaper clippings re. Marvin H. Pope, various (Box 33P, Folder 923)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1976-1993, n.d.; Series VIII
  - Black madonnas: poster and postcards (Box 34P, Folder 924)
  - Posters of Indian goddesses Kali and Durga (Box 34P, Folder 925)
  - Postcards of St. Teresa of Avila, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 926)
  - Ugaritic prints: statues of Ugaritic gods and goddesses, Ugaritic tablets, etc. (Box 34P, Folder 926)
  - "The Ancient Alphabets," a pamphlet by Hani Za'roura from Syria, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 928)
  - Color postcards of art from the Damascus Museum, Syria, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 929)
  - Color postcards of the Holy Land (Box 34P, Folder 930-931)
  - Archaeological map of Jerusalem, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 932)
  - A map of the Kingdom of Saudia Arabia, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 933)
  - Maps: Syria and S.E. Anatolia, Greece and the Aegean" (Box 34P, Folder 934)
  - Color postcards of Egyptian art; one postcard of Indian art (Box 34P, Folder 935)
  - Caption copy and list of line drawings for "Song of Songs" (Box 34P, Folder 936)
  - Cartoons re. "Song of Songs", n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 937)
  - Lithographs from Paul Wunderlich's "The Song of Songs" (Box 34P, Folder 938)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible volume of Song of Songs: print of the cover of an Etruscan sarcophagus; Pope wanted this image to be printed on the book jacket of his SOS AB commentary, Doubleday refused, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 939)
  - Line drawing of embracing couple, taken from an Etruscan sarcophagus, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 940)
  - Prints and photocopies of illustrations intended for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs. (Box 34P, Folder 941)
  - Prints of illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 942)
  - Negatives of illlustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 943)
  - Prints of illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 944)
  - Line drawing of a warrior for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 945)
  - Negatives of illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 946)
  - Photographs of line drawings/illustrations for Song of Songs AB vol., n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 947)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs: Hebrew text of Song of Songs arranged in a floral design; prints of the goddess Kali, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 948)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs: illustration of a winged Athena carrying a corpse, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 949)
  - Miscellaneous illustrations intended for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs (Box 34P, Folder 950)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs re. death, feast, hunt, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 951)
  - Illustration for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs: plaque of a fertility figure from Iraq, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 952)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs: fertility figures, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 953)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs: Artemis at Ephesus, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 954)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs: layout of illustrations with corresponding descriptions (Box 34P, Folder 955)
  - Miscellaneous illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 956)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs: prints of goddess Kali, the Virgin of Poland, Ishtar (Box 34P, Folder 957)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs: drawings with a lotus theme, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 958)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs: various black line drawings and tracings (Box 34P, Folder 959)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs: drawings of necklaces, belts and bands found on Mesopotamian figurines (Box 34P, Folder 960)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs: drawings of the eye goddess, misc., n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 961)
  - notes on illustrates for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 962)
  - list of illustrations/acknowledgments for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 963)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs: photograph of a statuette of Baal, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 964)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs: line drawing, copy of early Corinthian art, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 965)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs: love scenes from Ugarit, n.d. (Box 34P, Folder 966)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs: negatives of images of Kali, Baal, Anat, and Mesopotamian and Corinthian art (Box 35P, Folder 967)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs: funerary reliefs, n.d (Box 35P, Folder 968)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs: misc. prints and negatives (Box 35P, Folder 969)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs: misc. prints: ecstasy of St. Teresa of Avila, terracotta figure from Harappa, etc., n.d. (Box 35P, Folder 970)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs: photograph of a statuette of Baal-Hadad, n.d. (Box 35P, Folder 971)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs: Ugaritic art, n.d. (Box 35P, Folder 972)
  - Illustrations for the Anchor Bible vol. of Song of Songs: SOS misc., n.d (Box 35P, Folder 973)
  - Dead Sea Scrolls Slide set; other Dead Sea Scroll slides; two boxes of lecture slides; slides of Syria; boxes of misc. slides, probably used in lectures, 1993; various dates (Box 35P, Folder 974)
  - cassettes of Pope's lectures: "Some afterthoughts on Solomon's Super Song"; "The Book of Job"; "Hosanna/Help, Please!"; cassettes of lectures by Ernest Nicholson: "God and His People: Covenant and Theology in the Old Testament" and "Theology of the Covenant since Wellhausen"; cassette of a sermon by Dr. Jack Van Impe entitled "Ten Middle East Prophecies and Christ's Return"; cassette of "Shalom from Jersualem" a monthly radio program; cassette of Arabic music; untitled cassette of a lecture by a Syrian monk, and bits of the liturgy in Aramaic (?), 1976-1985, n.d. (Box 36P, Folder 975)
  - film entitled "Ugarit"; film of the Morse College Holy Humor seminar; one unmarked film, n.d. (Box 37P, Folder 976)
- Offprints and Papers Collection, Series IX
  - Boxes 1-10 (Box 1–10)
  - Boxes 11-20 (Box 11–20)
  - Boxes 21-30 (Box 21–24, Box 24a, Box 25–30)
  - Boxes 31-40 (Box 31–40)
  - Boxes 41-50 (Box 41–50)
  - Boxes 71-80 (Box 71–80)